Welcome back and today in even driven
programming we are going to set up
producer. We have already done the
cluster setup. Today we will see
producer setup.
But before we start
if I show you that
if we are trying to set up producer, it
is just a one line of code.
All you need is this auto wiring which
is provided by a spring framework itself
a spring boot.
Kafka template and using this you just
need to do send.
topic
the key
and the value. That's all.
You are able
to publish an event to a cluster.
But
there are lot of things happen behind.
Okay? And if you see
the configurations, there are so many
configurations. See, these are all
optional configuration.
All you need is this.
Like which
broker
this producer need to talk to. You only
need
one configuration that is the broker.
Like which broker this my producer need
to talk to.
Okay?
Apart from this all this configuration
are optional. All you have is one line
of code
and producer is done.
But
we will not touch very high level.
We will try to go in depth. What happen
when you do
.send? What happen after that? Okay? So
let's start without wasting any more
time.
So cluster setup is already done. Now we
are proceeding toward producer.
So before we proceed with producer
setup, let's understand the producer
workflow itself.
So when producer do send
what happens?
When producer try to send a message, it
does not immediately send it to the
broker.
Okay? Instead,
message goes through multiple stages.
Okay? Inside the producer itself before
any network call happens. So, there are
multiple stages which
your event or your message pass through.
Let's understand each stage one by one,
which is very, very important. Okay?
Say,
this is the
Kafka template dot send message we have
to send. We have provided the topic
name,
the key, and the value, the message
which you want to publish.
After you done that, inside this send,
what happen is
the first stage is
serializer.
So, our message or our event, whatever
this, okay?
Is generally a Java object.
But, Kafka understand only bytes. Kafka
do not understand a string, custom POJO,
JSON, nothing. All it understand it
bytes.
And that's where your serialization is
required. Kafka does not know what is
the data type of our message,
whether it's a
integer, string, custom POJO, JSON, etc.
And for that itself this stage exist.
And if serialization stage fails,
message will not move to the next stage.
Okay? So, in serialization stage, what
happen is two things happen.
So, key is serialized and value is
serialized. So, this two,
key and value, because these two things
ultimately is stored
in Kafka.
Okay? So, you can say that these two are
actually serialized.
Every serializer implement this
interface. So, there is an interface
public interface serializer. Okay?
Every serializer there are already so
many built-in serializer present.
String
serializer, integer serializer, long,
double, float, short, JSON serializer.
All this
implement this
serializer interface.
We don't have to write any of this.
These are all exist. Okay? JSON
serializer is used when you have
to convert any POJO.
Okay? Plain old Java objects.
So, that
JSON serializer can be used.
But yes, we can also write our own
custom serializer.
Sometime what we have to do is we have
to remove sensitive fields before even
sending.
Okay? We have to encrypt the data before
it converted to bytes. Okay?
So, in that case we can write our own
custom serializer.
So, stage one is clear?
While we will do the implement, the
setup, in that way in that part I will
tell you how to
add serializer. But first step is to
understand it.
Okay? So,
have you understood the first part why
serializer is required?
The second stage is partitioner.
Okay? So, now let's say your key and
value both are converted to bytes. Okay?
Now this
pass to the partitioner.
And also, if you open this, there is
some class called I think Kafka producer
class.
So, if you see this Uh, Kafka producer
class, they have do send method.
In that, you can so uh see this stages
itself. So, let's see.
First is serialize.
After serialize, they might have to a
partition.
Okay? So,
we can you can also put a debugger point
in this class, and you can also check
this stages.
Uh, second is partitioner. So, at this
uh stage,
your event, your message goes to which
partition, that is decided.
Okay? So, what input it takes here, if
you see, the partition
partition.dot
So, partitioner.partition, it calls
this. It calls this interface, this
method.
So, it takes your topic, key, key bytes,
value, value bytes, cluster. So, this is
the input.
See, we have already So, you have a key,
you have a value. You have already
converted them to the bytes.
So, you have your topic, key, key bytes,
value, value bytes, and the cluster.
You pass it to the partitioner. What it
return? Partition number.
For this topic,
what's the partition number this event
should go?
Okay? So,
this is the work of the partitioner.
So, there are multiple cases.
The case one is the partition explicitly
provided.
So, when we do send,
right? In that, it has multiple
overloaded methods.
So, we can make use of one method that
topic, we can also provide a partition
number directly itself.
So, in that case, you can say that this
is like does nothing. You have already
provided with partition
your message has to go.
The second case is if key is provided.
So, this ensure the same key always goes
to the same partition.
Like in the cluster I have showed you,
right? Cluster setup also or
architecture itself.
That whatever the key you have provided
it will make use of like, okay, hash
like mod
partition number.
So, some formula it will do
and it will come up with the
partition number.
Like this.
Okay?
So,
you are using this overloaded method
where you provide a topic, key, and the
data.
Okay, and on this key the partition run
this formula.
Like hash of whatever the key bytes you
have provided mod number of partitions
available. And it come up with the
partition number.
Case three is no key is provided.
Now, this is also very important. So,
there is also one more overloaded method
send where you have only topic and the
value. There is no key.
Okay, no key, no partition. So, now in
which partition it should go?
So, generally
we say that it's round robin strategy.
Okay, let's say for this topic you have
three partition, partition zero,
partition one, partition two for topic
A.
Generally when we say that
if you don't provide key
what it will do producer will do round
robin. First it will pick P0, then P1,
then P2. After that P0, P1, P2.
This is generally you can say that
a pre-Kafka strategy, pre-Kafka 2.4
strategy.
From Kafka 2.4 and onwards
a sticky partitioning strategy is used.
I will explain you this
but after the next stage because there
is one more twist.
Okay?
So, let's keep this in our backlog now.
Okay, after the next stage I will cover
record accumulator,
then I will come back to this again.
Like what is round robin strategy,
which is like pre-Kafka 2.4 version, and
what is a sticky partitioning strategy.
Sorry. [snorts and clears throat]
Okay.
So, now let's say that in the
partitioner we able to know the
partition number.
>> [snorts]
>> The now next stage is record
accumulator, very very important stage.
So, here if you see,
so serialization done,
partition done.
After that it does accumulator. append.
Append the record to the accumulator.
What is this?
What is this record and I tell you this
is very very important.
So, it's an in-memory buffer inside
Kafka producer
that collects event per topic partition
wise
and group them into batches, very
important. So, understand with this.
Let's say you have a topic order events
and you have three uh let's say multiple
partition. So, it
collect the event
topic partition wise. Topic is order
events, partition zero.
All the events would be stored here. It
group them.
Okay?
Similarly, topic is order event but
partition is P1. So, any like partition
will decide, right? Partitioner will
decide
that for this topic partition for this
event
need to go into this topic and this
partition. So, what record accumulator
will do?
It will just collect them.
Topic and partition wise. Okay, for this
topic, this partition, let me collect
all the events.
Similarly, whatever the partition
partitioner will say that, "Okay,
any event for this topic and this
partition, it will just collect it."
So, it will create a batch.
So,
from producer
to your
Kafka, you can say that your broker.
It's not like one one event it will go.
Event one, event two, event three, no.
It always goes into batches. And your
one batch can have multiple events,
which is grouped by topic and partition,
which is very important. Because you
know that a topic can have many
partition. And the partition can reside
in multiple broker.
Broker one,
broker two.
So, it has
topic A, partition zero. It has same
topic A but partition one.
So, you can't mix topic partitions,
right? So, that's why it group based on
topic and partition, so that
it club all the events
which need to goes to one broker.
Okay? So, that it don't have to open
multiple or send multiple network
requests.
>> [cough and clears throat]
>> Sorry.
So, now we know that
producer always maintain topic partition
wise batch.
It send batch to the broker, not
individual events.
Now, I will come back to the point where
I showed you
that
when you don't provide a key,
pre-Kafka 2.4 version, it's round robin
strategy. And from Kafka 2.4 onwards,
it's sticky partitioning strategy. What
does it mean now?
Now, it will make more sense.
So,
consider this example that
you have like topic order event, you
haven't provided any key, and this is
the event one.
Like your message.
You want to put into topic order event,
but key you have not provided.
Event two, event three, event four,
event five, like this. And for this
order events, we have, let's say, three
partition.
This is our setup, and this is the way
we are sending the message with no key.
Now, what would happen?
So, pre-Kafka 2.4, less than Kafka 2.4,
it follow round robin partitioning
strategy.
So, partition, what it will do, it has
the knowledge of this. Okay. For
order-events
topic,
I have three partition, P0, P1, P2.
So, what it will do, when event one will
come, it will assign P0.
Event two will come, it will assign P1.
Event three will come, it will assign
P2. And now, round round robin.
Event four, again, P0. Event five, P1.
Now, the partition
partitioner send the request to the
record accumulator. Record accumulator
will
batch it, group it.
Order event partition zero. So, E1 will
go, and E4 will go. So, they are batched
together.
Order event partition P1, E2 and E5,
they are batched together.
And similarly, order event P2,
uh only one, E3 are
in a batch.
So, now here, if If see,
we are creating multiple batches
which are in a small small size. Let's
say this batch capacity to keep 100
events, let's say.
But now it has only two. It has only
two.
It has one. So, three batch we are
creating.
So, problem with this approach is that
batch size is very small and therefore
multiple network call required
from producer to Kafka broker.
Which can be improved further with the
sticky partition strategy when the key
is missing. Which is like you can say
that in Kafka greater than equals to
2.4, a sticky partition strategy is
used.
What it does?
How it is different from the round robin
partition strategy?
So, in this one, let's say event one
come.
Okay?
There is no key.
So, what it will do this partition? No.
That for order events, I have three
partition P0, P1, P2. What it will do is
it randomly randomly pick one partition.
Okay? And it will stick to it for this
topic.
So, what you got is that order events
uh value is your event one, but key is
null. So, what it will do is for this
topic order event, out of this three
partition, it will pick randomly one.
Let's say it picked P1.
Now it stored this into in memory.
It will say that, "Hey, order event,
I need to stick to P1."
Now,
this event one,
it will just check its memory and say
that, "Okay, P1."
It will pass to the accumulator.
This event one need to goes into the P1
of order event, so that is done.
Now, next time when E2 comes,
it will check its uh sticky memory. You
can say that uh this
has partition stored in its memory
itself that, "Okay, for this topic,
order event,
uh key is null.
For this event, which partition I need
to go? Do I have any sticky memory?"
Yes, order event is P1. So, it will
again
say that, "Okay, for this event two,
put it into P1."
So,
event two also goes there, event three,
event four, event five. So, all the
events
of this topic
for which this has created a sticky
memory, you can say,
it will
only return the same partition number,
and record accumulator will keep on
adding it.
So, now here in this case, you will see
that instead of three batch, we have
only one batch created.
And that will ultimately one network
call to the broker.
Now, why it is not round robin? You can
say that, "Okay, now next time, let's
say Let's say
uh batch
capacity is
five itself.
Okay, it can't hold more, and five is
already done.
Now, let's say event six is coming.
Okay, when event six is coming, it will
again say,
"Partition again will say that, 'Okay,
because in its memory for this topic,
this P1 is sticky.' Okay? So, now event
six comes, it will say that, 'Okay,
store into the P1.'
Now, record accumulator
has to create a new batch.
Okay, this batch is already closed, you
can say that. This is closed and ready
to be dispatched to the broker.
So, it will create a new batch for
order-events
partition P1.
So, even six would be stored here.
But,
this record accumulator will also send
one more information that this is a new
batch.
Okay? It It opened a new batch.
So, now partition know that a new batch
is created, so it will also update its a
sticky memory that hey, what it will do
is randomly pick a game
from out of this. So, randomly
it could be again P1, it could be P0, it
could be P2, anything. But, it will
update its that okay, order-events
now randomly it will pick. Now, let's
say it's P2.
Now, this is its a sticky.
Okay?
So, that's what it follows.
Until and unless your batch is not
closed, you can say that your batch is
not closed.
Your partitioner keep
a map.
Like for this topic, this is the
partition. It is stored this
information, and it will always whatever
the event come for this topic, it will
always return the same partition, and
your record accumulator will keep on
filling that
batch for that topic, for that
partition.
And once it is full,
okay?
It
for the new event, it tells the
partition that hey,
this is a new batch I have created. So,
from the next event, your partition
might
send the partition to the same batch,
the same partition, or different
partition.
Okay?
Because it has updated its now a sticky
memory.
So, this is clear.
Why I
uh
told you this round robin and sticky
for this record accumulator because
it's not just round robin. After round
robin, it there is a batch concept also,
which is very important.
Okay? Because ultimately batches goes
to the broker.
Sorry.
Okay.
Now, let's move ahead.
Now, question one thing which you might
get is how to control this batch.
What should be the batch size?
How much time I should wait before I
I can say that this batch is now is
ready.
So, there are two ways.
One is batch.size. So, these are all
configuration.
Okay? If you don't provide this, there
would be a default values.
So, batch.size default is 16 KB.
So, means maximum memory allocated per
partition batch.
Okay? Per batch, this is the 16 KB is
the maximum default.
Okay?
Maximum size it can have. Once this size
is reached, the batch is closed and it
is ready to be dispatched to the broker.
Okay? For example, you are one event
size is 1 KB. So, means this batch can
hold around 16 messages.
And when batch size is reached,
batch is closed and it is
ready for sending.
Ready for sending.
Now, you can say that okay, what if
traffic is less and even I have put 16
KB, which can hold 16 message,
what if there is only five message, but
traffic is less. Like I am not getting
more events. What to do? Will it keep on
waiting forever?
No.
There is another control
linger.milliseconds.
linger.ms equals to 10 milliseconds.
Okay?
This is the maximum time producer will
wait for more records to fill the batch.
Once this time is over
whatever the batch
you have been created with events, it
will close the batch and send it.
So this makes sure that producer do not
wait indefinitely for a batch to fill
when the traffic is slow. You can say
that.
Okay?
So in this example
whether your batch is full or not
producer maximum wait only for 10
milliseconds. After 10 milliseconds, it
will close the batch and it will mark it
as ready to be sent to the broker.
So this is the two ways through we we
can control the batch.
Again, these are optional. Default
values are already there. Even if you
don't set, default would be used.
>> [snorts]
>> Now let's move to the next stage. We
have done serializer.
In this we have converted object to the
bytes. Partition, here we got that okay
we which partition this event should go.
Record accumulator, here we have
created batches. Batch one, batch two,
batch three.
Topic partition wise, topic partition
wise.
Okay?
Now once that done, it passed to the
compression.
So batches which are ready to send
are compressed to reduce network usage.
Okay? So there are various compression
you can say that algorithms
like gzip
Okay? Snappy.
So, we can use one
algorithm, you can say that.
And what it will do is it will reduce
the size of our batch. Earlier, let's
say our batch size is 64 KB.
After compression,
it become 18 KB.
Okay?
So,
and also one more advantage is that
Kafka will store this compressed
batches.
So, it will also save disk space, too.
Very important part.
And compression is
like I would say that very important
because you know that, right? How
compression works? Like
it do certain enhancement in the like
how you are representing the data. Okay,
repetitive like if you have many
repetitive words, it will just replace
it with like some
let's say two.
So, that it it do some internal
efficiency. It brings some internal
efficiency to represent the same data
which later can be again converted back
to original form.
Okay?
So, compression I would say that
it's not See, we have multiple Gzip,
Snappy.
There was always
also that you can say that hey,
uncompressed. You don't want to
compress, also.
But I always say that
use compression.
This will save memory because you know
that
the Kafka is store
the event into disk.
So, that
is one advantage where you will save the
disk space.
Another,
you you will reduce your network usage.
So, from producer to broker when the
payload size is less,
your throughput will increase.
Okay?
So, if you are using uncompressed, I
would say that uh
revisit it again and make use of one of
the algorithm.
How to use it? I will show you when we
will set up. Again,
if you don't set it, there's already a
default.
Okay? Uh but yes, I will show you that
how we will set up when we will
uh
move to the setup stage.
So, serialization is done, partition is
done, record accumulator is done,
compression is done. Now what?
Now after that, it will goes to the
sender thread.
Last stage, you can say that.
Your application thread never send data
to the Kafka broker.
So, let's say this is your application
thread, right? This is your application
thread.
So, your application thread, if you see,
if you open the code,
so it has your application thread what
it has done is it has serialized it.
It has partitioned it.
After then, it has
record accumulator. It has invoked this.
It has
done this. Your application thread done
this. Your application thread done this.
Your application thread
put your event into the record
accumulator buffer memory.
Now it will create batch. Okay? It will
compress it. Okay?
After that,
what
is your application thread does further
task? No.
See, after that,
once you have submitted your task to the
record accumulator,
your application thread work is
finished. It just return future.
Okay? So, it just get free.
Okay?
Now, it will
just this application thread is now
free.
You can say that. It is free. It can
perform some other task.
Now, there is a entry of sender thread.
So, Kafka has
one thread.
What it will do is
it will look for the batch which are
ready to be sent.
Okay? So, sender thread responsibility
is that check record accumulator for
ready batches.
Okay? So, you can say that stage three
stage four
these are all record accumulator part.
Compression is also a
part of record accumulator. Record
accumulator create batch.
The batch which are ready
and closed, it will compress it.
Okay?
And keep it ready to send.
Now, who will send? Sender thread.
So, what sender thread will do? Sender
thread check the record accumulator for
ready batches.
Okay?
There is now one another level of
efficiency.
Now, let's say that I have
batch one
batch two
batch three.
Now, let's say this is broker.
Broker one
partition zero, this is a leader.
For partition, let's say five also, this
is a leader.
Similarly, broker
two
partition one, for partition one, this
is a leader.
Like this. Okay?
Let's say we have three partition, two
brokers. So, let's say broker one is
leader for partition zero and partition
two.
Partition two, and for partition one,
broker two is the leader. Let's say, P0,
P1, P2.
P0 leader is broker one.
For P1, leader is your broker
two.
And for partition two, the leader is
your broker one. So, broker one is a
leader for two partition.
Now, let's say that the
batches which are ready to send. Let's
say this is for
topic A partition zero. This is for
topic A partition two. This is for topic
A partition one. Let's say these are and
these are
This is for topic A partition zero.
Topic A partition two.
Topic A partition one. Okay, this is the
setup.
Now,
at this record accumulator, what it has
done is it has created batches. Like all
the events which are for topic A
partition zero,
it has accumulated it. All the events
which are for topic A partition two,
accumulated together.
Similarly, in the batch three, all the
events which are for topic A partition
one are grouped together. Now, sender
thread need to send it to the
leader broker for this partition.
So, who is the leader for topic A
partition zero?
Broker one. So, this need to be sent to
the broker one.
Who is the leader for topic A partition
P2? Topic A partition P2 leader is
broker one. So, this also need to be
sent to the broker one.
Who is the leader for topic A partition
uh one?
Topic A partition one, broker two. So,
this need to be sent to the broker two.
Now, sender thread do one level of
another thing that okay, this batch need
to be sent to the broker one. This batch
need to be sent to the broker one. Why I
will send two requests?
So it will further
wrap it up in one request and make only
one call to the broker one.
That's what I have mentioned here.
It group batches by broker leader.
Okay, batch for topic A partition zero
leader is broker one.
The same thing which I have explained
here the
same I have just written it here.
So if there are multiple batches which
need to goes to the same broker instead
of sending multiple requests send a
request further enhance the throughput
by further grouping or you can say that
it just wrap in one more request it just
wrap that batch one batch two pass it to
the
broker one.
Okay, in just one call itself.
So now another responsibility
of this sender request is when you got
it that it first identify who is the
leader broker for the partition.
Then it group the batches based on the
broker leader.
Then it will send the request to the
network client.
Okay.
Based on the response from the broker.
Okay, let's say if there is a failure.
Okay, it will also handle the retries
also.
And ultimately it invoke the callback.
So I had told you that the application
thread
submit the request to the record
accumulator and just get free.
They can just so it return a future
object. So here if you see it return a
future object. This is the
future record metadata.
Now application thread just do like when
complete.
In Java I have already discussed
completable future. It just say that
when complete.
So now what would happen is your
application thread is like busy doing
some other task.
Now when the sender thread invoke the
callback,
okay, let's say it say that hey, mark it
as complete.
So it
invoke
this piece of code.
Okay?
Now based on your event publishing
success, failure,
your application, how you want to handle
it, you can do that.
>> [clears throat]
>> Now one question might comes to you that
hey,
can we control the sender thread like
how many threads I want? No, you cannot
control it. Kafka manage it internally.
There is no way
in my knowledge that we can't control
this sender thread.
But yes,
the one thing we can control
Sorry.
The one thing which we can control is
>> [snorts]
>> see this one.
Let's say you have your This is your
cluster, Kafka cluster.
This is your broker one,
broker two.
Now let's say this is your producer.
What your producer will do, your
producer here in this case the sender
thread.
So sender thread has
create one TCP connection with the
broker one, create one TCP connection
with the broker two. Because it need to
send the batches.
Right? It need to send the batch.
The one thing which we can have, you can
say that the control is that
max in flight request per connection we
can set.
So see,
now the sender thread send the request.
Let's say this is the message it sent.
This message is nothing but a batch.
Okay?
This batch
can have, you can say that multiple
event.
Okay, or you can say that this batch or
this request you can say
can have like multiple batches itself.
I told you right it further group the
batches.
And those batch have further like
multiple events.
For now I'm just saying
message.
Now when the sender
thread
send one message now this broker has to
process it. So it might take certain
time.
Okay.
So
one thing which we can control is that
this number max in flight request. In
flight means that
sender thread has sent the request to
the broker.
But broker is currently processing has
not sent the response back to the
sender thread.
So sender thread will just simply wait
or you can say that what it will do.
So with this
max in flight connection
what it say that okay you can send
maximum up to five messages which are in
flight.
Okay, so what it will do is the sender
message uses the same TCP connection.
And on the same TCP connection it can
send five messages.
Which are in flight. So this is in
flight, this is in flight, this is in
flight broker one will work okay when
the broker one will finish processing it
will keep on sending the response back.
Okay, that for this message this is the
result failures acknowledge or retry you
have to do
certain transient failure something.
So but this is one more you can say that
uh
control which we can do maximum in
flight request.
So, now you can see that
why producer has so much high throughput
is that
sender thread already does one thing.
In one message, it can have like one
message generally you can say that it
can have a batch. A batch can have
multiple event. Or it can further in the
message itself can further group the
batches itself which ultimately pass
through the one broker.
Okay.
So, your one message itself can have so
many events.
And also
in one connection itself we can set max
in flight let's say five which is the
default. So, you can send like this five
messages at
once.
Okay.
So,
message two, message three, message
four, message five. Like this you can
send five messages.
Okay. Now, this five messages broker one
can continue working and on it on it.
It's an in flight. That's why the name
in flight. Okay. And when the broker one
complete, let's say it complete message
two
it will send the response.
Completed message four, it will send the
response to the sender thread. Okay.
So, now
here if you see in one connection
we can send let's say five message. So,
we have two connection. So, in the
second connection also the maximum it
can send is five messages.
So, 5 + 5 10. 10 messages it can send in
parallel you can say that.
On two connection
10 messages it can send.
While those are in flight. Messages are
in flight.
And each message is not like 10 message
means 10 event. No. Again, I'm saying
one message can have like okay one batch
which one batch can have multiple
events.
Even that one message can have like
group
of multiple batches which ultimately
goes to the same broker.
So, one message can have multiple
events.
So, that's what I just mentioned here.
>> [snorts]
>> This parameter max in flight request
controls the maximum number of
unacknowledged request unacknowledged
request
the client will send on single
connection before blocking.
So, we have three TCP connection. Let's
say three broker. Let's say three
broker. So, means three TCP connection.
So, means maximum 15 request can be in
flight across the cluster at once.
Across the cluster, let's say this
broker one five five if you have broker
three five here. So, 15
messages 15 requests in flight at once
in a cluster.
Sorry.
>> [snorts]
>> Now, here comes a very important part.
An interviewer or might be if you're
working your architect might ask you
this.
Whenever you use max in flight request
greater than one
and your retry is also greater than
zero, let's say.
What if
what if the
broker one
like so broker one got this five request
message one
message two
message three
message four message five. All are
currently in flight in flight in flight
in flight and it is processing.
What if message one got let's say some
error transient error
and it return the transient error.
Now, the sender
thread need to retry it.
Okay, we have set the retry. Let's say
it need to retry.
So, the problem is
when the max in flight request per
connection is greater than one, means
you have multiple messages
and retry is also greater than zero,
then there is a risk of message
reordering.
How?
Let's say request A,
request B, only two requests. Request A,
request B, both are in flight.
Request A fails with some transient
error. So, this got failed with
transient error and it's sent to the
sender thread some transient error.
Okay?
While your broker start working on this
message two and this is persisted
successfully on the disk on logs.
Now, the sender thread
>> [snorts]
>> does retry for this request A.
And after that it got success also,
because it's a transient error.
Transient error means that if you retry,
temporary error, you can say that.
Now, after retry
from the sender thread, let's say
this is also gets succeeded. Now, it
will also stored in the log.
But now there is a mismatch in the
ordering. You wanted request A and then
request B.
But what ultimately stored on Kafka logs
for this partition is that first B is
stored.
So, this events, whatever the events are
present here,
those will get stored first. They will
get all like offset
one, offset two, offset three, like
this. After that request A events will
get and further offset, let's say 100,
101, like this it will go.
So, now ordering is changed. Like this
events for the request A should be
before the B request.
So, how you will handle this when you
set this property?
Max in flight request,
you can't set one
because then you like your throughput
will decrease.
This is important to increase the
throughput.
Okay?
Retry is also important. Sometimes there
is a transient failure, so
it should retry. So, both are important.
We can't just set it one.
Okay?
You will solve the issue, reordering
issue, but
on the cost of throughput.
So, generally default is five here.
Okay? Generally default is five. Max
in-flight request per connection is
five. Retry is also like let's say two
or three times.
So, reordering issue
can come. So, to solve this,
there is something called idempotency.
We need to set it true. I will cover it
separately because it is important.
Okay? So, I will cover it as separate
part.
But,
remember that
we need to like this is very important
part and we need to cover this.
Now we know a bit about producer. Now we
can move to the setup part, setup phase.
So,
I will I will cover setup phase in the
next part, but I hope in this part you
got that when you do dot send,
there are so many things happen.
Okay?
And uh
for each stage,
how to do a setup, we will see in this
next part, but I hope this stages are
clear.
Like what each stage internally does.
Okay? Any doubt, let me know. We can
discuss further into the comment
section. Bye.